Let's get right into it and see how to write a class in Python.
现在我们直接来讲解如何用 Python 编写类
If you haven't worked with classes before,
如果你之前没有接触过类
the syntax might be a bit confusing,
语法可能会有点难懂
but we'll go through some code step-by-step.
我们将逐步讲解一段示例代码
For now, I'm going to show code using Jupyter Notebooks,
我将暂时使用 Jupyter Notebook 演示代码
but later in the lesson you'll be modularizing code into Python scripts.
但之后你将使用 Python 脚本编写代码
In the top cell,
在第一个单元格中
I've written a Shirt class,
我编写了一个 Shirt 类
like what we were just talking about in the previous video.
就像在上个视频中讨论的那样
The class has color,
该类有 color
size, style, and price attributes.
size、style 和 price 属性
I also wrote a method to change the price,
我还编写了更改价格的方法
as well as a method to output a discounted price.
以及输出折扣价的方法
The code cells that come after this first one shows
第二、三个单元格展示了
some examples of how to instantiate shirt objects,
如何实例化 shirt 对象
so that you can see how to use a class in a program.
告诉你如何在程序中使用类
I'll start at the top of the file and work down.
我将从第一个单元格往下开始介绍
The very first line tells Python that I'm going to write a class,
第一行告诉 Python 我将编写一个类
and then I name the class shirt.
然后将该类命名为 Shirt
Good coding practice says to capitalize the first letter in a class name,
良好的编程实践规定 类名首字母要大写
but your code will still work even if you don't do this.
不过即使首字母不大写 代码也能运行
You can put parentheses after shirt or not,
你可以在 Shirt 后面添加括号 或者不添加
the code will run either way.
代码都能运行
The next line takes care of
下一行则规定了
initializing all of the attributes with the appropriate values.
如何用相应的值来初始化所有属性
Remember, that a class represents a blueprint,
注意 类表示的是一个范本
hence I'm setting up the color,
因此我设置的是
size, style, and price of a generic shirt.
通用 shirt 的 color、size、style、price
You'll see how the initialization of a specific shirt object works in a minute.
稍后你将了解如何初始化特定的 Shirt 对象
There are two things about this that might look a bit funny, the underscore, underscore,
有两个地方看起来有点奇怪
init, underscore function, and also the self variable.
__init__ 函数和 self 变量
The init function is built into Python.
init 函数是 Python 的内置函数
Python knows to use this function to create a specific shirt object.
Python 可以使用该函数创建一个特定的 Shirt 对象
Again, bear with me for now,
暂时先记住此函数
I'll go back to this in a minute.
稍后我会解释的
The self variable can be tricky to understand at first.
self 变量一开始不好理解
Self stores your attributes like color, size,
self 会存储 color 和 size 等属性
et cetera, and makes those attributes available throughout your class.
并使这些属性在整个类中都能使用
Self is essentially a dictionary that
self 本质上是一个字典
holds all of your attributes and the attribute values.
用于存储所有属性及其属性值
Checkout the change price method to see how self works.
请查看 change_price() 方法 看看 self 的工作原理
I pass in self as the first method input so that I can have access to the price.
我将 self 作为方法的第一个输入写进括号 从而能够访问 price 属性
Self has the price stored inside it as well as
刚提到 self 存储了 price
the other attributes like color, size, and style.
以及 color、size 和 style 等属性
Self is always going to be the first input to
如果你想访问属性
your methods if you want to access the attributes.
那么 self 将始终是方法的第一个输入
Note as well that the change price and
同时注意 change_price() 和 discount() 方法
the discount methods are like regular Python functions.
都很像普通的 Python 函数
For example, Python functions do not have to return anything,
例如 Python 函数不是必须要返回内容
so like in the change price method it doesn't return anything,
因此在 change_price() 方法中 它没有返回任何内容
it only changes the value of the price attribute.
只是更改了 price 属性的值
The discount method on the other hand does return
同时 discount() 方法则返回了内容
something it returns the discounted price.
它返回的是折扣价
Again, the shirt class is just a blueprint.
重申下 Shirt 类只是通用范本
I'm going to run this first cell and then move on to the second cell.
我将运行第一个单元格 然后再说第二个单元格
Let's see how to actually use this class.
现在来看看如何使用这个类
The following are some examples.
下面是一些示例
If I want to create an actual shirt object I use this syntax here,
如果我要创建实际的 Shirt 对象 则使用这样的语法
this is called instantiating an object.
称之为实例化对象
Notice that the syntax in order matches the init function,
注意输入值的顺序需要与 init 函数保持一致
I'm initializing this specific shirt with the color,
我赋予属性一些值 包括颜色、尺寸、风格、价格
size, style, and price,
来初始化这个特定的 Shirt
just like in the init function.
就像 init 函数一样
Python is going to call the init function to initialize this t-shirt object.
Python 将调用 init 函数来初始化这个 Shirt 对象
I'm going to run the code cell.
我来运行代码单元格
Okay, the output here is a shirt object and then all of those funny numbers and
这里的输出是一个 Shirt 对象 至于末尾的有趣数字和字母组合
letters at the end is Python giving the location in memory where the object is stored,
是 Python 在告诉我们该对象在内存中的存储位置
but this isn't very useful unless we actually store the object in a variable.
但是这样并没有什么用 除非将对象存储在一个变量里
So in the next code cell,
因此在下个代码单元格中
I'm doing exactly that,
我将把对象储存在变量里
I'm going to run this code cell and now I've stored
我将运行此代码单元格
this shirt object in the variable new shirt.
现在这个 Shirt 对象存储在了变量 new_shirt 里
The new shirt variable has a color,
new_shirt 变量具有相关的
size, style, and price associated with it.
颜色、尺寸、风格和价格
You can access these attributes this.syntax.
你可以使用这个点记法访问这些属性
So, I'm going to run this next code cell and you'll see the output.
我来运行下个代码单元格 你将看到结果
Scrolling down, you use same.syntax to access the methods as well,
向下滚动 你还可以使用相同的点记法访问方法
except you also need to specify any inputs that these methods require.
但是需要指定这些方法所需的任何输入
For example, to change the price,
例如 要更改价格
I call the change price method with a value of 10.
我将调用 change_price() 方法并传入值 10
Running this code cell,
运行此代码单元格
you now see that the price attribute has changed from 15 to 10.
现在看到 price 属性从 15 变成了 10
The same goes for the discount method.
discount() 方法也一样
I input 0.2 to the discount method and it returns a value of eight,
我在 discount() 方法里传入 0.2 结果返回值 8
because that's a 20 percent discount off the price.
因为这是打八折后的价格
In this last part,
在最后一部分
I instantiate three shirt objects and then store those objects in a list.
我实例化了三个 Shirt 对象 然后将这些对象存储在一个列表里
The reason I'm showing you this is to emphasize that
举这个例子的原因是
these variables are like any other Python variable.
我想强调这些变量和任何其他 Python 变量一样
Here are the results.
结果是这样
Once I've stored the shirts into the T-shirt collection list,
先将 Shirt 存储到 tshirt_collection 列表中
I then run a for loop and print out the color of each shirt.
然后运行 for 循环并输出每件衬衫的 color
If you're new to object oriented programming,
如果你第一次接触面向对象编程
all of this might feel overwhelming.
刚刚讲解的内容可能听起来有点难
My suggestion is to watch this video again and then move on to the next part
我建议你重复观看本视频 然后再转到下一课
of the lesson where you can play around with this code and write your own class.
下一课的内容是进一步探索代码并自己编写类
The most important thing you can do is practice.
最重要的是练习
Write your own class, run the code,
自己编写类 运行代码
and debug any error messages you get.
并调试出现的任何错误消息